Lucas Acuña

092802483 · lucasacuna.luj@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/lucasacu Montevideo, Uruguay.



SUMMARY

IT professional with two years of experience in IT infrastructure management, Salesforce and web development. Eager to innovate and make a meaningful impact through teamwork and continuous growth, currently expanding expertise and knowledge to cloud computing and DevOps.

EXPERIENCE

Tier 3 - Active Directory Support Engineer Microsoft

Sep 2023 - Present

- Delivered Tier 3-4 technical support for Active Directory and cloud environments, specializing in Infrastructure, Windows Server, and Azure integrations.
- Resolved over 200 complex global incidents of varying severity, achieving 100% resolution using advanced troubleshooting, in-depth analysis, and PowerShell scripting, while consistently meeting established SLAs.
- · Utilized advanced log analytics to identify Kerberos failures and authentication errors in complex network environments.
- · Identified and resolved system vulnerabilities, ensuring enhanced security and stability in enterprise Active Directory environments, providing security recommendations to over 90% of clients.
- Led cross-functional training sessions to improve team knowledge on critical topics like PKI, Kerberos, and DNS, fostering stronger collaboration.
- Improved team performance metrics by 150%, earning multiple 5-star customer satisfaction ratings and outstanding feedback.
- Recognized as a top performer for consistently delivering exceptional service and effective solutions.

Salesforce Developer

Nov 2022 - Sep 2023

- · Developed custom solutions using Apex, Lightning Web Components (LWC), Flows, and declarative tools to streamline business processes.
- Enhanced process efficiency by 35% through the implementation of Salesforce solutions, including automation and custom logic.
- Successfully implemented Proof of Concepts (PoC) and demo projects to showcase new solutions and technologies to clients.
- Achieved Platform Developer 1 and Salesforce Associate Certifications, demonstrating technical expertise and commitment to professional development.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Directory Services - Active Directory Cloud Academy - Microsoft | 2023 - 2024.

Salesforce Platform Developer 1 Certificate Salesforce.com | 2023.

Testing - Development Jovenes a Programar | 2023.

Computer's Engineering Degree UDELAR | 2023 - Coursing.

PHP - MySQL Web Development Course.

Taller de Informatica | 2022.

TECH

LANGUAGES

Active Directory

Windows Servers

Azure

- Salesforce
- PHP
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- MySQL
- Office 365

English: Advanced. Spanish: Native.